cosmeticsbusiness.com 2009-04-29

# cosmetics business

HPCi Media Limited Website personal data “Privacy Policy”

**HPCi Media Limited Website personal data “Privacy Policy”**

HPCi Media Limited (“HPCi Media”) is committed to protecting your personal information when you are using our services. This Privacy Policy relates to our use of any personal information you provide to us through the cosmeticsbusiness.com websites. 

This privacy policy explains the following: 

• what information HPCi Media may collect about you;  
• how HPCi Media will use information we collect about you;  
• when HPCi Media may use your details to contact you;  
• whether HPCi Media will disclose your details to anyone else;  
• your choices regarding the personal information you have provided to us;  
• use of cookies on our websites and how you can reject these cookies. 

As set out above, HPCi Media is committed to safeguarding your personal information. Whenever you provide such information, we are legally obliged to use your information in line with all laws concerning the protection of personal information, including the Data Protection Act 1998 (these laws are referred to collectively in this Privacy Policy as the "data protection laws"). 

Our websites contains hyperlinks to websites owned and operated by third parties. These third party websites have their own privacy policies, including cookies, and we urge you to review them. They will govern the use of personal information you submit or are collected by cookies whilst visiting these websites. We do not accept any responsibility or liability for the privacy practices of such third party websites and your use of such websites is at your own risk. 

**_What information will HPCi Media collect about me?_ **

When you sign up to participate in or receive a service from any HPCi Media website, such as newsletters, competitions, live chats, message boards or register with the single universal online registration system used across different parts of cosmeticsbusiness.com we may ask for personal information about you. This can consist of information such as your name, e mail address, postal address, telephone or mobile number or date of birth. Different web pages may ask for different personal information. 

By entering your details in the fields requested, you enable HPCi Media and its service providers to provide you with the services you select. 

HPCi Media also uses cookies (see below for details) and collects IP addresses (an IP address is a number that can uniquely identify a specific computer or other network device on the internet). We use analysis software to look at IP addresses and cookies for the purpose of enhancing your user experience. This information is not used to develop a personal profile of you and the log files are regularly purged. 

**_How will HPCi Media use the information they collect about me?_ **

HPCi Media will use your personal information for a number of purposes including the following: 

• for "service administration purposes", which means that HPCi Media may contact you for reasons related to the service you have signed up for, as set out below (e.g. to provide you with password reminders or to notify you that a particular service has been suspended for maintenance);   
• to contact you about a submission you have made to the websites, including any content you provide.   
• to personalise the way HPCi content is presented to you;   
• IP addresses are used to identify the location of users, the number of visits from different countries and also to block disruptive use; and   
• to analyse and improve the services offered on cosmeticsbusiness.com. e.g. to provide you with the most user-friendly navigation experience.   
• Where HPCi Media proposes using your personal information for any other uses we will ensure that we notify you first. You will also be given the opportunity to withhold or withdraw your consent for your use other than as listed above. 

**_When will HPCi Media contact me?_ **  
HPCi Media may contact you: 

• in relation to the functioning of any service you have signed up for in order to ensure that HPCi Media can deliver the services to you;   
• where you have opted to receive further correspondence;   
• in relation to any contribution you have made to cosmeticsbusiness.com, e.g. on HPCi Media message boards;   
• to invite you to participate in surveys about HPCi Media services (participation is always voluntary); and   
• for marketing purposes where legislation permits this and you have not told us that you do not wish to be contacted.  

**_Will HPCi Media share my personal information with anyone else?_**

We will keep your information confidential except where disclosure is required or permitted by law (for example to government bodies and law enforcement agencies) or where you have permitted third parties to contact you with relevant information about the business and markets in which you operate. 

Offensive or inappropriate content on HPCi Media website 

If you post or send offensive, inappropriate or objectionable content anywhere on or to cosmeticsbusiness.com, or otherwise engage in any disruptive behaviour on cosmeticsbusiness.com, HPCi Media may use your personal information to stop such behaviour. 

Where HPCi Media reasonably believes that you are or may be in breach of any of the laws of England or Wales (e.g. because content you have posted may be defamatory), HPCi Media may use your personal information to inform relevant third parties such as your employer, school e-mail/Internet provider or law enforcement agencies about the content and your behaviour. 

**_How long will HPCi Media keep my personal information?_**

We will hold your personal information on our systems for as long as is necessary for the relevant service, or as long as is set out in any relevant contract you hold with HPCi Media or HPCi Media's corporate retention schedule (this is a database that defines which documents should be kept and for how long). In the case that you wish to cancel your registration as a cosmeticsbusiness.com member, once an account is deleted a red flag goes on the database and, while people cannot use the personal information, it stays on the system for a period of one year for administration purposes before being deleted automatically. 

Where you contribute to cosmeticsbusiness.com we will generally only keep your content for as long as is reasonably required for the purpose(s) for which it was submitted. For example, HPCi Media will only keep copies of entries to a photographic competition for the duration of the competition. However other projects (e.g. the People's War website) are likely to have a longer, or even permanent, duration. 

**_Can I find out what personal information HPCi Media holds about me?_**

Under the Data Protection Act you have the right to request a copy of the personal information HPCi Media holds about you and to have any inaccuracies corrected. (We charge £10 for information requests and will require you to prove your identity with 2 pieces of approved photographic identification.) We will use reasonable efforts to supply, correct or delete personal information about you on our files. 

Please address requests and questions about this or any other question about this Privacy Policy to the Data Protection Officer, HPCi Media, Paulton House, 8 Shepherdess Walk, London N1 7LB. 

What if I am accessing HPCi Media websites outside the UK? 

www.cosmeticsbusiness.com is published in the UK by HPCi Media. For international users accessing the site from outside the UK all personal information submitted by you to the site goes directly to HPCi Media and will be processed in accordance with this Privacy Policy. 

**_Changes to this Privacy Policy_**

This privacy policy may be updated from time to time so you may wish to check it each time you submit personal information to any cosmeticsbusiness.com website. The date of the most recent revisions will appear on this page. 

**_Cookies Policy_ **

What is a cookie? 

A cookie is a small amount of data, which often includes a unique identifier that is sent to your computer or mobile phone (referred to here as a "device") browser from a website's computer and is stored on your device's hard drive. Each website can send its own cookie to your browser if your browser's preferences allow it, but (to protect your privacy) your browser only permits a website to access the cookies it has already sent to you, not the cookies sent to you by other sites. Many sites do this whenever a user visits their website in order to track online traffic flows. 

Cookies record information about your online preferences and allow us to tailor the websites to your interests. Users have the opportunity to set their devices to accept all cookies, to notify them when a cookie is issued, or not to receive cookies at any time. The last of these means that certain personalised services cannot then be provided to that user and accordingly you may not be able to take full advantage of all of the cosmeticsbusiness.com features. Each browser is different, so check the "Help" menu of your browser to learn how to change your cookie preferences. 

During the course of any visit to cosmeticsbusiness.com, the pages you see, along with a cookie, are downloaded to your device. Many websites do this, because cookies enable website publishers to do useful things like find out whether the device (and probably its user) has visited the website before. This is done on a repeat visit by checking to see, and finding, the cookie left there on the last visit. 

**How does HPCi Media use cookies?**

Information supplied by cookies can help us to analyse the profile of our visitors and help us to provide you with a better user experience. This can be achieved through personalisation of your web pages or analysing user activity to determine what is more popular and what is not.
